<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Journal on 大道至简</title>
    <link>https://qiref.github.io/tags/journal/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Journal on 大道至简</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>cn-zh</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 20:52:23 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://qiref.github.io/tags/journal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20250630 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/30/20250630-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2025 20:52:23 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/30/20250630-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today, It was so hot. I took a walk alone after dinner . I often do that in recent days, and liked the feeling. last week, I have checked my body on hospital , the doctor told me I shouldn’t eat too much and take exercise. that true. after finished my walk. I felt comfortable.&#xA;The day, I learnt a new word “accumulate”, and now , I&amp;rsquo;ll practice the new word in a sentence:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250625 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/25/20250625-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jun 2025 22:14:48 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/25/20250625-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today, I watched a video in the youtube, It’s said wasting time is killing your life. That’s sound horrible. But when I rethought about it, I understood . Every time I said I’ll do it later, the fact is I’ll never do it. that‘s human nature, people always want to stay comfortable zones. so do I, In these days, I realized how important the time is. There are so manny great thing I want to do, but I spent so much time to the useless thing in the past.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250624 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/24/20250624-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2025 18:02:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/24/20250624-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today, I resolved a complex problem, now, I reviewed the process, found a lot of experience I could learn .&#xA;First, when facing to complication that I have never seen. I should be more patient , the problem that I resolved cost one day to finish. In the process, I felt anxious , frustrating, but never gave up. in the end, I found the solution.&#xA;Second, I must gather enough information before starting, in other words, the context of the problem must be clear.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250619 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/19/20250619-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Jun 2025 22:30:42 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/19/20250619-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today, I didn’t know what to write. It was difficult to write English journal everyday. But that’s what matters. see it. that phrase I have used yesterday. The best way is practicing constantly while learning English.&#xA;Let me see, what is the most impressive thing today. The first thing I can remember is ….&#xA;Unfortunately, 10 min later, I still cannot know what to write. 😂😂&#xA;I list some alternatives to words amazing , this what I have learnt today.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250618 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/18/20250618-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 21:18:08 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/18/20250618-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>I often think that I was stupid in the past life. It will be better If I did something or not did something at that time. so, I regred my dicision, But when I rethink that, That was me too, those things are apart of my life, I should accept it eventhought it was not so perfect . I cannot always be right. But I should know what is better, what is a wrong decision.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250617 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/17/20250617-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 10:50:56 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/17/20250617-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today I watched a presentation of TED on youtube, and it said we human beings can make friends with stress. In someway, The stress is benefit to our bodies. It depends on how we consider it. If we think stress is bad for our life, yes , those who will often be anxious while being stressed. But ,on the other hand, If we are under stress, it means that we are ready to handle it, speed of heart is higher, so we can resolve the difficult situations, we’ll not be anxious about it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250616 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/16/20250616-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jun 2025 11:15:43 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/16/20250616-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today, I showed my English journal to my darling, I wanted to shared my thought to her because of trusting. But her reaction astonished me , &amp;ldquo;why not me in your first journal?&amp;rdquo; she said, what a amazing girl she was! she always gave me surprise.&#xA;Util now, she envy our son, Yesterday was father&amp;rsquo;s day, we went shopping in the evening, And she bought expensive clothes that&amp;rsquo;s suit me fine , I was so cheerful that day, After that, we went home, she said to me that I was worth owning its, and I was so moving to heard that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250615 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/15/20250615-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jun 2025 10:26:11 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/15/20250615-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>This is weekend, As usaul , I went home after finished my work, My son ran to me and hugged me , I loved that moment!&#xA;The next day, After lunch, he looked so tired, and wanted to go sleep, but he was too young to sleep by himself, just a two years old baby. Then , I picked the baby up, he lay on my shoulder, and we hung out in the room, 5 min later, he felt asleep almostly, he saw a peice of cookie on the table, and wanted to eat it, Then， I gave the cookie to him, he slept while eating cookies, Wow, He looked so busy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250613 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/13/20250613-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 10:18:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/13/20250613-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today is a sunny day ，I walked to my company as usual in the morning. And listening the POC English audio. I saw a lot of mushrooms on the ground, and One of them was so big its looked asdonished. At the time,I wanted to say something using my poor English , Unfortunately I forgot the vocabulary of mushroom, I felt disappointed of myself. But when I arrived at my company, began to took off my earphones, I heard a word mushroom, Suddenly it was seem like remember something, I opened a dictionary APP, checking the vocabulary , That was amazing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250612 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/12/20250612-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 21:19:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/12/20250612-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today, I begin to write my journal of English Learning. And this is the first one.&#xA;I will write my thoughts or some new words, phrase about my learning English every day. In theses days, I have listened POC ENGLISH video in the youtube, that&amp;rsquo;s is high quality video about English learning. I will pay more attention to the video. By the way , the POC ENGLISH has their own website, there is a lot of blogs in that website, all of them are pretty good .</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
