<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Notes on 大道至简</title>
    <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Notes on 大道至简</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>cn-zh</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 10:18:38 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://qiref.github.io/note/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>20250613 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/13/20250613-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 10:18:38 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/13/20250613-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today is a sunny day ，I walked to my company as usual in the morning. And listening the POC English audio. I saw a lot of mushrooms on the ground, and One of them was so big its looked asdonished. At the time,I wanted to say something using my poor English , Unfortunately I forgot the vocabulary of mushroom, I felt disappointed of myself. But when I arrived at my company, began to took off my earphones, I heard a word mushroom, Suddenly it was seem like remember something, I opened a dictionary APP, checking the vocabulary , That was amazing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>20250612 English Learning Journal</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/12/20250612-english-learning-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Jun 2025 21:19:25 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2025/06/12/20250612-english-learning-journal/</guid>
      <description>Today, I begin to write my journal of English Learning. And this is the first one.&#xA;I will write my thoughts or some new words, phrase about my learning English every day. In theses days, I have listened POC ENGLISH video in the youtube, that&amp;rsquo;s is high quality video about English learning. I will pay more attention to the video. By the way , the POC ENGLISH has their own website, there is a lot of blogs in that website, all of them are pretty good .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Another Note on A blogdown Tutorial</title>
      <link>https://qiref.github.io/note/2017/06/14/another-note/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://qiref.github.io/note/2017/06/14/another-note/</guid>
      <description>I just discovered an awesome tutorial on blogdown written by Alison. I have to admit this is the best blogdown tutorial I have seen so far.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
